Good evening and a very warm welcome to
one and all for Asian Paints investor
conference for Q4 FY2022 results.
Myself Arun Nair from corporate
communications.
Today on the panel we have Mr. Amit
Singhal, MD and CEO.
Mr. R. J. Jayamurugan, CFO and company
secretary.
And Mr. Parag Rane, GM finance.
May I now request Mr. Amit Singhal to
take you all through the presentation.
Mr. Amit Singhal, over to you.
A very good evening to all of you and
thanks for coming for the
investor conference for the Q4 financial
2022 results. I will take you briefly
through the presentation in terms of how
have been the numbers so that we can get
a quick idea in terms of what it is.
Just to recap,
Asian Paints has been delivering joy
since 1942 and as you all know we exist
to beautify, preserve, transform all
spaces and objects and bring happiness
and joy to the world. So you can see
practically all spaces is something
which you touch across with all the
objects which are there.
Just a disclaimer.
So overall when you look at the numbers,
finally a very
strong quarter is what I would say in
terms of what we have been able to
deliver.
The bases were very very strong with a
48% volume growth last year on the same
quarter and a 44% value on which
basically the volume growth has been a
strong 8% in terms of what we have been
able to deliver and a value growth of
about 21%
if we look at the overall decorative
business. The CAGRs over the two and
three years for both volume and value as
you can see are very very strong and
very
very very positive from that point of
view in terms of
staying the stating the intent of the
company in terms of the which way we are
headed over the various quarters and
that has been the very very strong focus
in terms of what we have taken. In terms
of the volume growth, the larger growths
obviously came in the months of February
and March because January was affected
because of the COVID third wave to that
extent. And we think that to grow 8% on
a 48% kind of a growth base, I think it
is really good in terms of what has been
delivered.
Overall, if you look at the picture
across the quarters,
if you see all quarters have been very
very strong
to that extent resulting in terms of the
year being also at a very strong 31%
volume growth and a value growth of 36%.
So, it's a very clearly
very robust performance in terms of what
you see.
Specifically, when we look at the full
year, today as I said, volume is at a
31% growth on a base of a 13% growth
last year and a value is at a very
strong 36% growth. So, despite the fact
that there would be a contribution
because of the price increases, I think
it's overall a very strong value growth
for the year in terms of what has got
delivered. And again here you see that
the CAGRs over 2 years and 3 years both
on the volume and the value are very
strong and very strongly positive. So, I
think that's clearly indicating that
overall the trajectory has been very
very strong over the years in terms of
what we have looked at in terms of our
growths on the overall top line.
Some qualitative things which are coming
which you would be definitely
interested. If we look at
you know, the growth T1 T2 centers in
the metros have done good double digit
growth especially in the luxury and the
premium range which is there.
And T3 T4 if you look at there have been
good growth here as well and there is
double digit growth in the economy range
here
to that extent. So there is a mixed bag
in terms of this thing but overall what
we see is that T1 T2 has done much
better than T3 T4 cities as a overall
performance in Q4.
As we see
today
that the growth was dented in Jan 22
because of the COVID. February and March
were very strong growth in terms of
double digits which we kind of got which
has given us the resultant 8% growth
for the quarter.
If you look at growth have been across
geographies and the highest obviously
has been in west in the eastern
geographies but other regions also have
been pretty good overall in terms of
what we have delivered in Q4.
Overall one of the focus of the
companies has been that we look at
technological innovation in a very
strong way and new products is a way to
that innovation where we are looking at
patents and we are looking at invention
disclosures
to that extent and today we see that the
overall new products are contributing to
almost like 14% of the revenues top
line. So I think that is a very strong
trajectory as far as the story of
innovation goes.
Waterproofing and wood finishes two
categories which has seen exponential
growth rates and here the competition is
not only the paint companies but what we
see is the competition being plethora of
multinational companies and other
players which are there.
The other business which has taken a big
surge in terms of what we see as far as
Q4 is concerned is the project
institutional business and uh this has
been across the cities uh from the
builder segment as well. Uh strong
growth coming more from the government
factory segment overall. And
waterproofing and admixtures have done
fairly well overall as part of the
imperative to kind of get into newer
construction.
So, this is possibly the highlights in
terms of what we look some idea in terms
of the innovation.
Uh we've got into world-class textures
now which are being offered and today we
believe that no one is able to offer
this range of textures at this cost in
terms of what we are giving and these
are tuned to the Indian climate
conditions. So, this is an innovation
which I would say that it is uh new to
the world so to so innovation which we
have kind of bought.
The other is that for the first time in
the category
we have looked at a fire retardant paint
uh which was not there. It was only in
industrial coatings but a fire retardant
paint for uh normal homes with a very
strong lotus effect technology which
means that today it prevents any water
kind of going inside the walls to that
extent. So, I think it comes with also a
anti-stain absorption. So, I think all
in all a very very superior technology
product which is coming uh
which we introduced this year. Then we
have Royal Glitz which is the top end
product which is there and I think the
key thing here comes in is that is it's
in the uber luxury space uh
with anti-crack durable coatings and
Teflon kind of luxury and protection
which kind of comes in. So, interior
products good innovation. Similarly in
the whole area of waterproofing wood
finishes a lot of products which are
unique for the first time for the Indian
market and based on technological
innovations to that extent. So, I think
uh the stress here is that some of these
products cannot be offered by
competition very easily because it is
either patented or in terms of coming
with a huge technology which is there.
So, to that extent, it is something
which we think will give us gains for a
long period of time.
If you look at the overall year, or as
we see, I think
distribution footprint which has been
the strength of Asian Paints is
something which we looked at
concentrating in a very big way.
We looked at
opening new retailers in big city
suburbs and T3 T4 cities in a strong
way. So, today we have a unique model
where we are now coexisting on a
distributor model and a direct dealer
model as well, which has given us
almost 15,000 retail points more this
year, taking our total tally to about
145,000
retail points, which itself is a very,
very strong number from the point of the
footprint across the length and breadth
of the country.
Uh when we look at product category,
again, as I said, expansion into areas
which have been very, very strong this
year, some of the things I just covered
for you, including new categories like
adhesives and DIY paints in terms of
what we have kind of got into.
The entire
thing as a leader, what we are looking
at is that we are increasing the per
capita consumption and enlarging the
whole paint market in a strong way. So,
new categories to fuel growth. We
entered the wood polish market, which we
can convert the French polish players to
a new product called Glo Max in terms of
what we have introduced. We have
introduced super economy emulsions,
which basically gets the unorganized
emulsion user into an organized emulsion
space strongly. And some of the
categories which I just covered, like
the fire retardant glass paints, floor
paints, which are really enlarging the
overall paint market in a very strong
way. And that I think is a task of a
leader in terms of looking at
continuously exploring newer spaces,
newer avenues, so that the per capita
consumption of paint really kind of
increases.
The other unique thing is that we have a
very unique painting service model. We
believe that globally this is the
biggest and the best service model. No
other company today even outside the
paint space has such a big model in
terms of what it is delivering. It is
across more than 240 towns with 150,000
trained painters and a customer delight
coming through an NPS measure in terms
of what we have put into place. And a
range of services which we are offering
through so that the customers are happy
taking this service. So we think this is
a very strong servicing edge which
cannot be replicated by anyone very
easily. Something which we have
propagated and we are growing it bigger
and bigger every year.
Some of the glimpses of the services
which we offer in terms of
the safe painting services and
waterproofing and other things which
comes as part of the overall painting
service which we have.
Uh we look at now the home decor
business and I'm sure a lot of you have
questions on home decor in terms of what
we are doing.
Today I think the home decor fair is a
very very strong foray where we are
looking at Asian Paints being a
foreigner in the inspirational and
exciting as a
exciting partner where we are also
partnering the customer in the home
decor so that we can make her dream home
come alive.
So this is a transition from the share
of surface to a share of space. So now
we exist not only between the on the
walls but between the four walls as
well. So this is a business I want to
re-emphasize. It is complementing our
existing business and adding to our
coatings business in a very big way
because the customer is the same and
therefore what you are expanding is a
customer life cycle. So you are
talking of more touch points in the
customer life cycle and therefore I
think it really invigorates our core
business as we kind of go forward.
Today,
our endeavor is to provide home decor
under one roof. Today, we are looking at
beautiful home stores across the
country. We have got 29 stores which
offer
kitchen, bath, sanitary ware, lighting,
tiles, flooring, furnishing, furniture,
doors and windows across one roof under
one roof to that extent. And in this
category, if you see,
today we own kitchen, we own bath, we
own sanitary in terms of man
manufacturing. We've just bought a
lighting company which is White Teak.
Okay, we have got into furnishings with
the company called GM Syntex where we
have done an alignment. And we have got
doors and windows through another
acquisition which we have done on
weather seal. So, the idea is that today
we are not looking at just procuring
products, but we are looking at making
our own products and Asian Paints having
a way of decor going very strongly. We
believe that today
by the end of this year, we would have
about 70 stores and we would be India's
biggest
chain of stores of home decor in terms
of how we see going it forward to that
extent. We have a central inspiration
model which is called the
beautifulhomes.com which offers
inspiration to the people. And we also
have a beautiful home service which is
offering personalized interior decor to
for professional execution which is
offered in now 9 to 11 cities as we look
at going forward. We also have a BH shop
which is offering a e-com kind of a
potential which is there to that extent.
So, if you see, all offerings are very,
very strong and it's a complete home
decor foray which we have built over the
last 2-3 years in a very strong manner
to that extent. As part of this, today,
as I said, we have made investments
across
the products which are there. Overall,
where today all products are getting
kind of made by us. In designer and
general tiles. We are making a green
field foray ourselves. In wardrobes and
vanities, again there is a green field
foray which we are getting into. And
today when you look at designer
wallpaper, we have set up a facility in
Jaipur. To extend rugs, we have done an
alignment with Jaipur rugs there. And as
I said, two new acquisitions which have
come. So today I think it's a unique
model which we have and it's a very
strong model which is spread over e-com,
physical execution, and services all
together which is a complete kind of a
facet which we are offering.
As I said, we aligned with this company,
we took over this company. Uh
we announced it on 1st of April 2022,
the White Teak company. It's a premium
lighting company and uh we feel that
it's a very strong alignment in terms of
what we have done. Secondly, we have got
this Weather Seal which is making uPVC
doors and windows. And it's a big
segment in terms of what we are gunning
at. And therefore, I think it gives us a
lot of advantage in terms of going
forward as we look at the home decor
category.
Uh obviously coming to numbers, we think
that home decor business this year
overall if we see all the businesses uh
would be about 4% of our total deco
business. Going forward, I think in the
next about 3 years we are aiming that we
can take it to about 8 to 10% of our
total business. And that also a
profitable business so that overall this
kind of really becomes a very strong
point of galvanizing the company into a
new trajectory going forward and adds to
the coatings business in a strong way uh
as we go ahead. So I think this is
something which is the story of home
decor which I wanted to quickly tell
you. Going on to the other businesses,
uh sorry, kitchen and uh bath which is
part of this.
Both businesses have been really
revolutionary this year. Uh kitchen
business has been delivering 100 plus
crores for the third consecutive
quarter. And overall if you see the
growths have been very very strong in
terms of the overall financial year it
has grown by 55% good growth in Q4 as
well. Similarly the bath business has
registered a very strong growth of 46%
and in Q4 about 17%. So overall we see
on a profitability front both businesses
are coming up fairly well.
Today kitchen business has reduced the
losses to just about minus two crores
this year over minus nine of last year
to that extent overall sorry over
business of minus nine over the full
year kind of a zone which was there
earlier. So today we look at
kitchen contributing to minus nine
crores which is much better than what we
did last year. In bath overall if you
look at this year we have done a four
crores kind of a
PBT which has come in to that extent in
the quarter it is one crore. So both
businesses strongly delivering on the
top and the bottom line and I think
today this is the future in terms of
what we are taking of the kitchen and
the bath business going forward in a
strong trajectory with good
profitability going forward.
Coming to international business this
business has been something where I
think it has been a very tough year
overall as we look at it.
In quarter four if we look at overall we
have still done a decent amount of
business which is there
overall to that extent
but if you look at the various regions
the highest growth comes in from Asia
where basically the revenues have been
stronger both in Q4 in the full year
followed by to some extent in Middle
East and South Pacific. Africa has not
done too well overall in terms of
looking at it. But the debacle this year
has happened more from the point of view
of profitability
given the very high amounts of inflation
we had taken some price increases but
not a commensurate in terms of the
overall increases to that extent. And
the second factor which is contributing
is the devaluation of the currency which
is in Sri Lanka, Ethiopia, and Egypt
overall to that extent. And that is why
if you see the numbers in Africa are
affected very, very strongly. So are the
numbers affected in Middle East to that
extent. Asia has done relatively better
in Q4. We have got some profitability,
but I think the whole thing what we are
seeing in Sri Lanka has put the overall
profitability down to that extent
this year. So on the whole, on the top
line, I think it is still a good growth
in terms of what we are seeing in
international business. However, from
the point of view of profitability, I
think the inflation has taken a toll
coupled with the currency devaluation to
that extent.
Uh going forward to the industrial
business, if we look at
the entire business which we call as the
PPG AP business, which is about the auto
OE auto refinishes and the marine paints
business overall to that extent. This
year has been a relatively good year in
terms of what we see. For a year, we see
a 32% kind of a growth. For the quarter,
we have a 19% growth which is there to
that extent.
In the other business, which is the uh
APPG business, which is a general
industrial business, which we see, this
has done phenomenally well. In fact, it
has grown by 51% for the year, clocking
almost close to 800 crores of business
which has come in. And in quarter four
also, the business has been very, very
strong. Uh I think the good part is the
profitability for both the businesses,
which is the
PPG AP as well as the APPG business has
been strong and we are seeing good
growths
on both the businesses together to that
extent. And therefore, I think
industrial overall has grown at a good
quick clip both in uh Q4 as well as for
the entire year.
Uh there are some exceptional items
which we'd like to draw your attention
to. Obviously, to today there is when we
put up a plan, we get some subsidies
from the state governments and the state
and the subsidies take a little bit of
time from the realization of these money
is really coming to us physically to
that extent and therefore what we have
looked at is basically
you know, creating a method where we are
looking at how to account for these
because the realizations of this are not
known in terms of when they will happen
to that extent and therefore we have
provided for
two amounts here. One is the 53.7 crores
which is what we have taken as one set
of subsidy which is there
which is for the previous years to that
extent and the second is what we have
taken as a subsidy of 31.1 crores which
is there which is
for the current year in terms of what we
are kind of assessing. So, I think these
are the two kind of subsidy
exceptional items which are kind of
coming which is impacting the profit.
The third is the
story in terms of Lanka where possibly
we are seeing that there is a currency
devaluation
which has taken place which has led to
almost
a recognition of an expense of about
48.5
crores towards the exchange loss and
second
we have company called Causeway there
which we had acquired sometime back and
there we are looking at an impairment
provision of about 13.5 crores as an
exceptional item on goodwill on
consolidation recognized on the
acquisition of Causeway. So, I think
these are the two two big items which
are coming which are affecting
you know, the overall profits at the
standalone as well as the console level
to that extent which are there.
We look at overall if you look at you're
familiar with this in terms of what we
had presented. Overall if you look at
from the point of view of gross margins,
I think this trajectory had gone down to
quarter two to about 35%
and then in Q3
we brought it to about 37% and in Q4
after the price increases in terms of
what we have taken, the gross margin is
quite good relatively speaking at about
40% to that extent. Helped also by price
increases in the fact that in Q4 we did
not see too much of an inflation. It was
just about 1% to that extent. So
therefore I think the good story is that
the gross margins are back to that
extent which is happening. Obviously I
think we'll have to watch out because Q1
story is now again inflationary which is
looking at about 5 to 7% kind of
inflation happening in Q1. Where we are
also we are taking some measures as we
kind of go forward.
Overall in the summary you look at the
standalone financials. So overall as we
said, we just discussed that on the net
sales there's a 22% kind of a growth
overall which has come in.
If you look at PBT PBT is a strong 14%
which you are seeing. This is before the
exceptional items. And if you see the
PAT PAT is about 10% for Q4. So these
figures are all for Q4 and I think they
are very very strong numbers because the
bases were very high to that extent
coupled with the fact that January was a
COVID month which was like a whitewash
month to that extent. So the quarter was
a two-month quarter in a way to look at
in that way.
If you look at the full year again I
think the standalone financials are very
strong a 37% net sales kind of a growth
which you are seeing overall. PBDIT
which is
also strong in terms of which has come
up along with PBT and the PAT numbers
which are there. Overall if you see the
PBDIT margins have
really improved in Q4 to that extent and
so have the gross margins as I said to
that extent. So the PBDIT margins uh
for Q4 are back to the
20.2%
which is there to that extent. So which
is a good recovery which has happened in
terms of the PBTI margins overall to
that extent.
Uh let's look at the console numbers.
Again, if you see for the quarter four
overall good numbers on net sales 21%
even in terms of PBT numbers if you see
uh you are looking at a a clear 13% kind
of a growth which is coming in the PAT
number and the PAT is flat because
obviously in terms of the exceptional uh
expenses we have taken and also the
global business which has possibly under
delivered overall to that extent.
Uh on the year front obviously
uh the top line numbers are good. The
bottom line numbers are affected overall
for the full year because of the global
performance and the exceptional items
which have come in terms of the overall
PAT which is there. But overall the top
line looks pretty good in terms of what
we have been able to deliver.
Uh in terms of dividends again I think
we have been a steady player in terms of
rewarding the shareholders to that
extent and for even the current year we
have given a 58.6%
payout to that extent and that is
something which is a reward for a
possibly a good performance in terms of
what has happened this year. So, I think
overall this trajectory has been fairly
good.
Uh some of the conditions as immediate
outlook as we see overall
uh as I said uh the demand conditions uh
can be a little tough. We don't know in
terms of what is going to happen, but we
are still confident that what we saw in
March and Feb and March I think uh the
trajectory should be good in terms of
going forward from the point of view of
demand. The only worry is that if there
is a COVID scenario which comes back or
uh the other big problem is the
inflation in terms of what is there. So,
for inflation obviously as we have
stated here we are taking some
calibrated price increases. We have
already taken two increases uh this uh
this quarter and we will see in terms of
if we have to take more increases going
forward. But we are putting in place a
very very strong structure for sourcing
and formulation efficiencies which we
can get so that we can counter the
effect of the inflation going forward
overall. Monsoons are supposed to be
good, so I think the trajectory of T3 T4
cities, we are confident that should
kind of pick up and should be good as we
kind of go forward. Global markets
challenges will continue for some time.
We don't think so the situation in Sri
Lanka is under control to that extent.
And Egypt and Ethiopia possibly will
fight back in the second half of the
year, but Sri Lanka would always
remain as a concern because it will take
some time to kind of take
you know, situation to kind of really
become normalized.
Just a brief thing on our journey in
terms of what we are taking as the ESG
and that is a very strong journey Asian
Paints has been kind of making over the
years. We have specifically looked at
environment, social, and governance
there. In the environment, strongly
looking at product stewardship as one
strong thing. Water, energy is something
which is a very strong objective which
we have kind of taken. And I think a
strong journey which is kind of pursuing
in those areas. As far as social is
concerned, strong amount of community
work which is happening. We have taken a
strong work of water. Water harvesting
and whole area of water stewardship is a
very strong area in terms of what we
have kind of invoked.
The whole area of making the entire
environment energizing, equitable, and
inclusive. I think those are strong
elements in terms of what we are kind of
bringing with our policies and looking
at giving that kind of empowerment to
the employees going forward to that
extent.
Finally, in terms of governance, I think
this has been a strong point at Asian
Paints and this is something
which we give a lot of kind of weightage
to and therefore we look at world-class
governance which is coming and therefore
engaging with stakeholders proactively
and looking at complete transparency in
terms of going forward as we look at. So
I think these are the responsible
choices we are making as far as the ESG
journey kind of goes. Some elements
which we will keep on highlighting to
you as we kind of go forward. I think
sustainable products is a very strong
zone, green seal, green show these are
some of the standards which we are kind
of
doing. We have about 187 products which
have been certified by the CII-IGBC
as a green pro products to that extent.
And similarly we are in the process of
eliminating a lot of ingredients. So for
example, lead was eliminated for a bias
way back
to that extent and subsequently we kind
of took out some of the elements so like
the respirable crystalline silica and so
and so forth to that extent. And this is
a continuous initiative which we kind of
keep on going to so that we are able to
kind of look at green products in a very
strong way.
The other is the whole area of the
carbon footprint and here is something
which is a continuous kind of work which
is going on not only with respect to our
plants but also looking at supply chain,
looking at our offices and the complete
360 degrees in terms of seeing what is
the kind of work we can do at shrinking
the carbon footprint in terms of going
forward.
Lastly, if you look at from the point of
view of the work which we have done, I
think it is pretty strong in terms of
that not only we are looking at
reduction in terms of what we consume in
terms of water but also replenishment.
And that I think is a big story in terms
of what we are doing and I think these
two kind of go together with respect to
the whole area of environment
conservation in a very strong manner.
Similarly, when we look at from the
point of view of electricity, okay, we
have 59% electricity from the renewable
sources which is coming and we have also
reduced the electricity consumption
internally. Strong objective both ways
which are coming. Similarly, the
industrial effluent generation is
something which we are reducing and we
are always already got into a zero
effluent discharge from our factories
and I think this is a very strong
initiative in terms of what has been
taken by us towards the environment. And
lastly, in terms of looking at plastics,
so more and more areas in terms of
recycling, collecting the plastic and
then seeing in terms of what we can do
about it in terms of going forward. So,
I wanted to kind of give you just a
flavor in terms of the ESG what we are
doing and there is lots more which can't
be put in three slides together, but I
think that is a big focus in terms of as
a leader we are taking in the industries
to make a mark that we are socially
responsible and those are the choices we
are taking.
So,
the other thing which is what we would
like to kind of do is as part of the
social thing which is concerned,
the CSR we have touched very very
strongly. Good numbers, we have a
vocational training, we do about 360,000
such trainings. In terms of the health
and hygiene, we kind of really cover
almost like 270,000
beneficiaries which are there. And in
terms of water management, that is a big
thing which we are taking possibly in a
lot of areas where plants where our
plants are located, where we are looking
at
recharging the water through various
initiatives to that extent. So, you can
see the plethora of work which is
happening in these areas which is
extremely strong.
So, these were some of the things which
I wanted to brief. So, overall in
summary, a strong quarter which is
there,
a range of initiatives, a lot of
innovation which has come in and we
believe that it has been a very very
strong objective for us
to kind of look at the full year being
delivered in this manner in in a COVID
kind of trajectory which we have seen
this year as well. Thank you so much.
Thank you, sir.
We'll begin with the Q&A now.
Today we have participants joining on
Zoom video platform and also via
teleconferencing platform.
Requesting all participants joined via
Zoom video platform, please use the
raise hand feature to ask your questions
to the panelists.
Kindly unmute when given a chance to ask
a question.
Please state your name and your company
name before asking your questions.
Participants connecting via Zoom video
platform can post their question on the
chat box, too, and we will ask on your
behalf.
Participants joined through toll-free
numbers, please press star one to ask
questions to the panelists.
Please also say your name and company
name before asking your question.
We would also request you all to limit
your questions to two numbers, please,
so that everybody gets an opportunity to
ask a question.
Our first question is from Mr. Avi
Mehta, who has joined us on Zoom. Sir,
please unmute yourself, state your name
and your company name, and ask your
question.
Hi. Uh this is Avi here from Macquarie.
I had two questions specifically. First
essentially is on the uh price uh the
input cost environment.
Uh what is the extent of price increases
that you are looking or would need to
pass on the current inflation? Or put it
differently, what is the crude price
that is there after these two price
increases that you've taken, which is
almost about 1% 2% odd?
Uh
if you could give us that sense,
and more broadly while you're kind of uh
answering that, if you could give us a
sense on the demand strength because you
did sound a little concerned on the
demand strength, and hence do you expect
that the time it will take to pass this
inflation will be longer than what it
has historically been?
That was my first question. Would Do
want me to go to the second now or uh
No, I'll answer this question.
So, overall when you look at from the
point of view of inflation, as I said
that
in quarter one which we are seeing an
inflation of close to about 5 to 7% and
this is across
the range of raw materials
including TiO2, solvents, additives, and
so on so forth to that extent. We have
taken roughly a price increase of about
1.8 to about 2% kind of an increase
which is spread across 2 months in terms
of increase on 1st of May and an
increase on 1st of June in terms of
there. In addition, we are looking at a
very strong initiative which we have
launched internally in terms of
sourcing and formulation efficiencies
and looking at alternate RMs in a very
strong way. And we think that we should
be able to cover a large chunk of the
inflation also through some of these
initiatives which are kind of coming in.
As we go forward,
we need to kind of balance the
consumer demand and also looking at the
price increases in terms of what we pass
on to the market as a responsible
industry leader to that extent and
therefore, what we are looking going
forward as some calibrated increases
which we might do depending on the kind
of savings which we are able to get
overall. So, I think
this is going to be a cycle which we
will continuously assess in terms of
going forward and look at possibly some
more calibrated price increases coming
as we kind of go forward depending on
the kind of savings in terms of what we
are seeing and also observing the
geopolitical situation in terms of how
it kind of really quietens down.
So, that's part one.
The second part is with respect to
demand.
We feel that in the quarter four,
the price inflation did affect a little
bit of a demand in terms of some of the
T3, T4 cities where possibly people kind
of really kind of deferred
their kind of pain demand since pain
demand is discretionary in nature to
that extent and some amount of
downgrading
from premium to luxury to economy in the
T1 T2 cities in terms of what we would
have seen. But as I said, February and
March were high growth
high double-digit volume growth numbers.
So which means we feel that the inherent
demand in the market would still kind of
play on. We must remember that people
have seen 2 years of solid kind of
uncertainty with because of COVID and
therefore there is still a latent kind
of demand which is still there which we
will which we will see in the coming
months and quarters to that extent and
therefore I feel that on the demand
conditions, if the current situation
persists, I think the demand condition
should be good.
You know, we are not expecting possibly
another COVID round coming to that
extent because I think the third round
of vaccinations have already started to
that extent. So I think as we kind of go
forward, we are pretty confident about
the consumer demand given the Feb-March
indications and whatever we see of April
currently to that extent going forward.
The only concern would be that inflation
should not play a spoilsport because if
the inflation goes up largely, we would
be kind of constrained to take larger
price increases in the market to that
extent which will definitely affect some
of the economy products in terms of the
demand which is there because finally
there is a price elasticity which
matters in terms of looking at consumer
purchases. But overall we are pretty
confident that the current situation I
think the consumer demand should be very
good because Feb-March and April we have
seen that.
Got it, sir. Got it. My second and last
question was on the home decor piece.
While we are looking to increase the
touch points, could you give me a sense
of the positioning?
Is this more of a quality product at a
you know, value kind of position or is
which is not available in the market or
is this more of convenience wherein all
products are available under one roof.
What will be Asian Paints focus over
here?
So, we are looking at something what we
call as the affordable luxury.
So, this is something which is kind of
pegged at premium kind of a level at but
at the same time a strong connotation of
the value for money which also comes in.
This is definitely not in the space of
Uber luxury at the top end in terms of
what we see but we look at possibly
affordable luxury in a very strong
manner and the whole theme is there that
Asian Paints is looking at a certain way
of decor. So, Asian Paints is
propagating a certain way of decor. It
is like fashion in terms of what you
propagate and as I said, I think the big
story here is that you are talking of
physical assets which are in terms of
stores. You are talking of a big service
which is a implementation service and
you are talking of categories where
there is a strong manufacturing angle or
an acquisition angle which we have
taken. So, I think all in all it kind of
really
gives a very strong signal that there is
a strong seriousness and there is a
strong kind of
inclination in terms of making this
category big.
Okay, sir. Thank you. That's all from my
side.
Thank you, sir.
Next question is from Avneesh Roy
who has joined us on the tele-calling
platform. Sir, please state your name
and company name before asking the
question. And also the question press
star one before unmuting yourself.
Hello.
Yeah, hi. This is Avneesh Roy from
Edelweiss.
Congrats on strong performance.
My first question is on waterproofing
and wood finishing.
So, you mentioned you have come out with
unique products and India first products
and these are based on patents and
technology.
So, now there is a very strong adhesive
player which has got a brand for a much
longer time frame and very strong
advertising also. So, when you say
unique and India first product, is this
against broader market or is this
against the adhesive player also?
Okay. So,
when we look at the waterproofing space,
Amish, we are looking at going forward
one being the, you know, undisputed
players as far as the retail offering is
concerned because if you look at from
the point of view of retail offering,
it is all about solutioning. It is about
giving a solution to the customer which
is very, very important in terms of what
is there. So, when we are talking of
unique products, for example, I'll give
you example of a product called
Hydrolock which we have come by which
has a unique technology that it kind of
really
doesn't allow water from inside to come
outside onto the wall. At the same time,
it has a technology where it when it
comes in contact with water, it forms
crystals. Okay, so that it blocks the
water to kind of come out. So, I think
the technology which we are talking are
very, very unique and no other, I
repeat, no other player today in India
and abroad has a technology like that
for a retail market in terms of what we
are placing and we think that today
we are the number one players as far as
the waterproofing category is concerned
as far as retail goes to that extent.
When you look at the category from the
point of view of
B2B segment and an institutional project
segment which is largely construction
and other players, there are a lot of
multinationals like the
the Fosroc, the BASF, Sika which are
players which are there to that extent.
We are today stepping up our chemistries
and looking at a lot of solutions which
we are launching which are in the spaces
of not only liquid membranes but other
kind of membranes which are kind of
coming
which are very strong technological back
products which are there to that extent.
So, today I think that is an area where
today only the multinationals are strong
and there is no other player in India
which is strong to that extent which is
there. And we are looking and targeting
in terms of getting some very strong
kind of business in that area also. I
can only tell you that
I think over the last 7 years we have
been literally looking at doubling the
numbers here in terms of going forward.
So, we think it's a very strong
objective and we are much ahead of any
other company in India world in terms of
looking at the technology in
waterproofing.
Thanks,
my last question is on
Sleek. So, you had acquired Sleek in
2017.
It's now almost 500 crore exit 100
business also and very strong 53% YoY
growth, 14% quarter-on-quarter growth.
Even after 4 years, mostly every quarter
there is a small loss. So, is it
advertising spend? And second,
Sleek after 4 years is still loss
making. You also made a comment that
home decor in the next
4-5 years I think you'll
on the you'll target a profit here. So,
taking Sleek into consideration, how
easy will home decor because that's much
smaller scale also versus the home decor
Sleek which is already 500 crore run
rate. So, how easy will profit be in
home decor in the next 4-5 years?
Okay. So, first of all I must say that
Sleek, you know, as we are seeing that
we last 2 years I think there are
quarters which Sleek has delivered
profit as well overall to that extent.
This year overall if you look at the
numbers, I think the numbers are very
strong. There is a very small loss which
is there. We are very confident that as
we come into the current year, I think
the current year would be a total profit
year for Sleek as we look at going
forward. Bath is already on a
profit trajectory in terms of what you
see this year to that extent. So, going
forward if you look at the home decor
category,
uh you know, whether it is the fabric
business or whether it is the beautiful
homes business or whether it is the
white teak business today, it's not that
people are not making money. The white
teak's business today is at a very
strong EBITDA of more than 20% in terms
of what they earn out of it. So, it's a
category where you can make money in
terms of going forward to that extent.
And therefore, we believe that
the trajectory which we are taking is
very strong and it would be a profitable
category as we go ahead. Even today,
what we are confident that both bath and
sleek will now continuously come into
the positive trend as we kind of go
forward. And so would other categories
as we look at the next about 2 to 3
years.
So, thanks, Amit. That was so nice.
Thank you.
Thank you, sir. Next question is from
Mr. Shirish Pardeshi, who has joined us
on Zoom. Sir, please unmute yourself,
state your name and company name, and
ask your question.
Yeah, hi, Amit. Good evening. Thank you
for the opportunity. Actually,
I'm delighted and you have a double
congratulations. One is the good set of
numbers and
I'm happy that in next 5 years, we will
interact with you continuously.
On that note, I have two questions. One
on domestic decorative. You said that
the demand condition
which are bit
hazy at this point of time. But you also
made a very strong comment that monsoon
in a row 3 years is going to be very
strong. So, in that context,
if you can help me because T3 T4,
the performance has been a little
volatile in last 3 to 4 quarters, but T1
T2 is very strong.
So, there are two parts to this
question. For FY22, if you can break up
what is T1 T2 contribution and what is
T3 T4 contribution to overall decorative
business?
And
the the touch point what you have said
is that is a stronger
outcome
of the need that we are expecting a very
strong growth in T3 T4. And how much
more we can grow in
in terms of distribution.
Okay.
So if you look at possibly the
contributions roughly for T3 T4 versus
T1 T2 would be in the zone of about 40
45 to 60 65 kind of a zone which is
there to that extent. So obviously I
think the contribution from T3 T4 is
higher in terms of what we see because
the number of towns are very very large
to that extent.
What we see is that the T3 T4 has been
fueled also by a large distribution
strategy as I pointed out to that extent
where there are new retailers coming,
new customers kind of coming into the
belt to that extent and that is
something which is also fueling the
entire T3 T4 market in a very strong
manner to that extent. So for the year
as I said the T1 T2 has grown faster
obviously to some extent which is there
because what we are seeing is that
because of the migration of the
customers which is happening the T1 T2
cities are getting more and more
populated as well to that extent. So the
T1 T2 contributions are increasing over
a period of time to that extent as we
kind of go ahead. Overall what I see
very clearly is that
the T3 T4 cities are also very strongly
dependent on the aggregarian income and
the aggregarian kind of forecast which
happens in the country.
As I said monsoons predicted are normal
this year overall.
So I don't see that there should be any
reason why we should not see good
growths in T3 T4 coupled with our
distribution which will kind of
continuously kind of continue to that
extent. The only one hitch which is
there is that today there is a certain
price elasticity. And for a consumer if
there are too many price increases which
are there, then I think to some extent
there is a deferment in terms of the
paint category which starts happening
over a period of time. So, I think that
is the only concern if the inflation
figure goes haywire. Right now, I think
it is still controllable to that extent,
but if the inflation goes haywire like
what we saw it last year to that extent.
Now, that could have an impact on the
demand, but I don't think so that is a
probability. So, therefore my prediction
is that I think for the coming year both
T3, T4 and T1, T2 should do quite well.
Okay. That's really helpful. My second
and last question is on the
international. So, I just made a rough
calculation out of 28,000 crore what we
have done around 13 and 1/2%
contribution comes from the
international business. So, my question
is specifically on you said that there
is some volatility in terms of currency
headwinds. Especially you you you called
out Sri Lanka and uh Egypt and Ethiopia.
and Ethiopia. So, just one question on
that
out of that 13 and 1/2% maybe broadly if
you can say that what how much quantum
of the business is at stake because of
these three geographies?
So, if you look at
you know, there is a Sri Lanka, there's
Ethiopia and there is Egypt. So, roughly
I would say that the quantum which would
get affected is about 5% or so, 5 to 6%.
Yeah.
Of
Of the total.
total group. Total group. Of the total
group. So, about roughly 40, 45% of the
IBU sort of portfolio.
Okay. Okay. Thank you. That's really
helpful Parag and Amit, all the best to
you. Thank you.
Thank you, sir. Our next question is
from Mr. Saumil Mehta who has joined us
on the tele-calling platform. Sir, you
may please ask your question now.
Yeah, thanks for probably Saumil Mehta
friend, Mehta, from Kotak Life. Uh two
questions. One is in continuation to one
of the previous uh questions wherein you
know we are looking to distribute in the
future by about 50,000 touch points.
That's a very harsh number. What I
wanted to understand is over the next
two or three years, uh should we believe
uh calculation from those touch points
similar to what we have today or
probably there will be cannibaliz-
cannibalization as the right extent?
A lot of the distribution will be in T3
T4 where the revenue per outlet is far
lower than what you are right now.
Sorry, I couldn't get your question.
Could you repeat it, please?
In terms of the distribution touch point
wherein we have added 50,000 more touch
points uh to an existing base, uh
how can we you know how should we look
at the contribution from those touch
points in over the next two or three
years? Can that number be similar to
what we do today in our existing T3 T4
cities?
That's my first question.
Okay. So, uh see today what we feel is
that uh
uh
we frankly feel that for the coming
four, five years to 10 years, I think uh
we don't see any saturation uh happening
in those numbers because uh I think
India is a rapidly expanding market to
that extent and we are kind of trying to
reach uh
uh the smallest of the towns and the
cities to that extent and each town we
find that there are more and more
retailers which are kind of coming given
the population which is there and the
low capita per capita consumption of
paint which is there to that extent. So,
that uh also is kind of increasing every
year overall. So, I think there is
nothing which we see as a
cannibalization happening in terms of
going forward there. Uh from the point
of view of contributions, as I said, uh
see the distribution expansion is
happening in both T1 T2 cities as well
as in T3 T4 cities to that extent. So,
therefore, uh you know, uh as I said,
both both the quantums are going to
increase to that extent and therefore
what we see that this would be a strong
source of contribution in terms of our
overall growth as we kind of go ahead.
At the same time, there is the existing
set of retail points which will also
continuously keep on growing to that
extent. So, I feel that while these are
larger distribution points, I think the
contribution which they kind of make is
good and substantial, but overall this
is a process which will continue.
Sure.
My second and last question, I believe
you were also in the race to acquire the
white cement business of
finally been acquired by a large player.
Do we expect any sort of you know
sourcing issues in terms of white cement
for our putty business or because
the the idea of asking if I look at from
last two to two or three years, the
increase in the putty business fraction
from paints and you know cement players
is far higher than the white cement
production. So, at some point in time do
we believe getting a better sourcing of
white cement for our putty business
might be a challenge?
So, as a strategy we keep on looking at
backward integration in a very strong
way. So, as you're aware we already make
one of the raw materials called
pentaerythritol in terms of what we make
ourselves to that extent. We are also
making a lot of emulsions and you know
certain ingredients which go into paint
to that extent. So, we keep on looking
at opportunities which are coming
whether it is in putty or whether it is
in paint to that extent which is there.
And as part of that foray, I think today
we would kind of be eager to kind of
look at saying that if there is an
opportunity which comes in terms of
investing in backward integration which
is a strong product from a long-term
paint consumption point of view and we
think that we can put some technology in
that to kind of grow that area, I think
we would kind of really be interested as
part of that and therefore
not particular to putty, but for all
other categories we look at a backward
integration in a very strong manner.
Sure. Thank you so much and all the
best.
Thank you, sir. Uh next question is from
Mr. Richard Liu, who has joined us on
the Zoom platform. Sir, please unmute
yourself, state your name and company
name, and ask your question.
Hi. Thank you for taking my question. I
just want to check Am I audible?
Yes, sir.
Okay, got it. Thank you. Um um I I just
want to check
uh you know, this this part on gross
margin with you,
uh if I look at your
you know, your standalone accounts,
uh the Y on Y growth in
uh in
COGS is about 51%.
Uh on that, you stated that your volume
growth is about 31%.
And that So, if I do it mathematically,
it implies that uh the increase in raw
material cost per unit
uh is about 17 to 18%.
Now, if I look at the inflation,
uh you know, on TiO2, which is what is
what the headline prices are against,
that is about 30%. Crude inflation is
about Richard, your voice is echoing a
lot, actually. I don't know. Your voice
is echoing a lot.
Uh
Okay. Uh is this better?
Uh yeah, a little bit. Yeah.
Okay. So, what I was talking about was
that uh you know, that if if I look at
uh the inflation in COGS per unit
uh you know, based on your standalone
accounts, uh that seems to be a bigger
So, the the the value growth in COGS is
about 51% against which you had a volume
growth of 31%, right? So, it implies
that
uh the inflation in uh
you know, the inflation in COGS per unit
is about 17%.
Uh against that, if I look at your
headline cost increases, uh TiO2
inflation at least as as far as what the
Bloomberg data suggests,
uh is about uh you know, 29 to 30% crude
is up 60 to 65%
so the blended would anywhere I guess be
about 35 to 40% now against a 35 to to
40% blended inflation and your RM index
you know the your your COGS published
data seems to suggest that your per unit
cost inflation is just about 17%
now I know you talked about internal
efficiencies etc etc but you know the
the
the inflation flow through factor if I
can call it that seems to be less than
50% of what your you know what the
headline raw material price data
suggests if you can just throw some
light on this is it because you had
inventory cover is it a lead and lag
effect and how should we look at this
playing out as far as FY23 is concerned
Okay see I think you will have to look
at possibly a different way of
calculation today because
if you look at possibly the last year
total inflation how we kind of peg it is
across various quarters in terms of we
see is
something like about a 32 to 34% kind of
a overall inflation in terms of what we
see against which we have already taken
a 24 25% kind of a overall increase
which is there to that extent you also
see the gross margins in Q4 we are
almost at about a 40% gross margin as
compared to possibly a year before which
was at something like about a 44% or a
45% kind of a zone so the deficit is
about you know if you see about a 4%
kind of a deficit which is there the
rest is kind of getting covered a lot by
the fact that
one the percentages like you can
calculate is that TiO2 goes in a certain
percentage across the variable kind of
products in a very different manner some
products TiO2 is higher some products
TiO2 is lower and similar story is for
solvents to that extent and in our base
there is a larger quantum of water based
anyway. So, we kind of get shielded if
there is a larger solvent base increase
which kind of takes place. So, which
means that for every company the kind of
inflation would be very different
depending on the product mix in terms of
what they have. So, from that point of
view,
today I think the gross margins in Q4
which are closer to about 40% as I said,
they are possibly 4-5% lower than a year
before kind of margins which were there
to that extent. So, I think we were
pretty comfortable to that extent. It's
only in Q1 where we are seeing another 5
to 7% kind of a increase against which
we have already taken a almost about a
1.8 to 2% kind of a overall increase.
So, I think the calculation which we
need to kind of take is different and
this way what you are kind of arriving
at possibly doesn't come to, you know,
the numbers which I am indicating to
you.
And and Amit, while we are at it, can
you also help understand the you know,
the so-called mix uh impact that we are
really seeing, right? I mean, that was
the number that used to be about 4 to 6%
depending on which quarter we are
talking about. Uh if I look at the
volume growth number is to the the value
growth number that you reported for Q4,
uh the so-called mix dilution impact
seems to be of the order of 10 to 11%.
No, so you're talking about the product
mix contribution in terms of solvent and
water based?
No, I'm talking about uh so so, you
know, based on the headline price
increase that uh you know, that that
you've talked about over the period of
time, uh I would think that the Y on Y
increase in headline paint prices is
about 30% plus.
Okay. Now, you reported about a 21%
value growth in the paint business
uh against which the volume growth is 8%
now. So, the implied pricing component
uh in your growth is just about 13% uh
versus your headline price increase of
more than 20%.
So, the mix the adverse mix impact seems
to be like 9 to 10% uh versus what it to
be about 4 to 6% earlier.
No, so Richard, see I think the other
problem which is there is that see for
quarter when you calculate it becomes a
different picture because there is a raw
material inventory of the previous
quarter which carries on to the
subsequent quarter for 2 months or so.
So it is very difficult to put a
quarterly number to that extent in terms
of looking at it. You'll have to look at
that yearly number in terms of what I
just gave you in terms of the overall
kind of margins in terms of what we are
enjoying to that extent as of now to
that extent and as I said that what
we'll have to look at from the point of
view that overall we have grown by a
value of about 37%
this year in terms of what you see.
We've taken price increases which are
about 24 to 25% in terms of which are
there in the total inflation which we
are talking is about 34 35% kind of a
zone. 32 to 34% kind of a zone. So I
think those are the numbers which
possibly you'll have to crunch to kind
of understand. I don't think so you can
go quarter to quarter.
Okay. Uh all right. You Okay, let me let
me ask something easier one. You talked
about You talked about
You know, you talked about non-direct
dealer, right?
You know, which which you are now doing.
Uh can you help us understand how big is
that part of the business? I mean, how
much is this this part contributing to
to that now?
So actually there is no concept like a
non-direct dealer because see there are
dealers which are there are paint
dealers and there are dealers which we
are touching through the distributor to
that extent. Okay. So I think this is a
combination where there are distributors
now who are supplying some part of the
paint, some part of the waterproofing,
some part of the
wood finishes to that extent. So it's a
mixed kind of a zone in terms of what is
there. So I would principally qualify
that with all these 1.45
lakh retail
outlets we are almost directly in touch
either with a dealer or or with
distributor.
Okay.
Uh all right. Uh I'll I'll I'll probably
take it up with Varun again and Mr.
Chairman will take it up with him. Okay.
Thank you very much.
Thank you, sir. Uh next question is from
Mr. Varun Singh who has joined us on the
tele-calling platform. Sir, please uh
state your name and company name and ask
your question.
Yeah, thanks for taking my question. My
name is Varun Singh from IDBI Capital.
Uh so, my question is on home
improvement business. Uh so, how uh do
we expect to share management bandwidth
given that we expect uh this category to
become uh
quite meaningful in next 3 to 4 years.
So, what changes uh should we expect
with regards to how we wish to drive
growth uh in all the three categories? I
mean, uh the kitchen bath business,
waterproofing, and the
uh other uh home improvement categories.
Uh if you can share some
uh thought over uh
over this point, sir.
So, uh what we are doing is that as and
when we are kind of adding these
businesses, so for example, the moment
we added a fabric
kind of business, we've added people
both from the point of view of sales and
uh marketing to that extent which is
there. Similarly, as the lighting
business kind of comes in and in terms
of other categories, so there is a set
of
uh design professionals we are adding
who have competencies with respect to
some of these categories. And then there
are sales people who possibly are able
to kind of leverage this uh kind of
categories uh to that extent. And there
is a third set of people
uh like the uh
people who are trained slightly
specially to kind of take it to the
architects and the designers to that
extent. So, what we are progressively
doing is that as and when we are adding
the categories, we are looking at adding
uh numbers in terms of that particular
category at the same time at the core of
it. We are putting a very strong design
structure which are there which will
include specialist who would kind of
come into each category and they will
look at new ranges, new designs which
would kind of come in which would kind
of match with what's really happening as
overall trends in India and the world.
Understood, sir. So, I mean broadly we
are not expecting months much changes at
the top management level with regard to
how we wish to manage the growth in
these three categories for next maybe
3-4 years.
So, today we are putting people at
GM and VP level as well in terms of some
of these categories to that extent, but
it's not that you know there is a very
strong you know that there is a CEO or
someone kind of coming as a category to
that extent. So, I think it is more at
the possibly mid-management to a senior
level in terms of what we're putting
along with the people who are coming to
manage the overall areas with the
network and also with the designers.
Understood, sir. And second question is
on
sir, the number that you have given is
quite encouraging with regards to more
than doubling the number of stores from
29 to 70 by the end of the current
financial year. So,
with regard to how we wish to sell the
products in the home improvement
category. Sir,
I mean why
how are you thinking with regards to you
know selling this product under one roof
rather than trying to sell it through a
distributor led model the way we have
changed the distribution model in the
paint business? So, any
insights if you can share on the
distribution approach why only through
stores and why not through distributors?
So, actually it's a dual selling
strategy which is there. The larger
propagators are basically the beautiful
home stores which I spoke of which from
29 we will take to that number of 70 in
terms of what we are talking of and
these stores would be bigger sellers
because they are kind of pitching to the
consumer the full kind of home decor at
one shot in terms of the whole area of
design and execution in a strong manner.
The other
structure which we have is that like we
have a structure in kitchen and bath
where we have a set of dealers and
distributors who are independently
selling kitchen and bath products.
Similarly, in fabric we have now almost
a 500 to 600 kind of retail set which is
kind of selling the fabric as well. So
and when we have acquired White Teak
they have their own stores which are
coming with the acquisition to that
extent. So as we kind of go forward you
will have a dual structure of selling
where there is
a consolidated home decor being sold
through beautiful homes and then each of
the categories is being sold by the
network in terms of what we create
around those possibly to be sold to that
extent and they they kind of sell only
one or two categories whereas the store
will sell close to about anywhere
between 12 to 16 categories.
I
understood sir. Thank you very much for
the detailed answer.
Thank you sir. Our next question is from
Mr. Amit Sachdeva who has joined us on
Zoom. Sir, please unmute yourself, state
your name and company name and ask your
question.
Hi, good evening everybody and
thank you for taking me thank you for
taking my question. My name is Amit
Sachdeva from HSBC.
I have set two questions. First coming
back on margins.
Basically, you know, last year as you
rightly say that 400 bps margin has come
down when it was used to be 44 and Q4 is
ending at 39 and a bit.
Now going ahead there two issues. One
basically there is some inflation as you
say in Q1 but can you also describe the
mix effect which could be different in
Q1 relative to Q4? And also in this
context, given the base is benign,
should we look at now gross margin being
sort of expansionary rather than
contractionary in this particular year
in FY20? What is your template thinking
right now? We are not asking for any
guidance, but seems like you're in a
comfortable position relative to
margins. Your volume base is very high,
but margin base is very benign. So, how
are you thinking about it? Related
question to that is a strategic whether
you in this whether Asian Paints as a
leader would like now margin to actually
hover around 41-42, but not go back to
44 because there are so many new
entrants. Would you like to keep the
maybe pricing discipline maybe enforced
in some sense that there is no question.
Is there a competitive angle to it as
well? That's question number one. Uh
uh
And then I'll ask my second one.
Okay. Uh
So, first of all, when we look at the
whole story of margins, uh see, going to
Q1, I don't think so that there is a
very strong change in the mix which kind
of really happens because
uh you know, the quarter-to-quarter, we
don't see too much of a mix change which
happens except for a little bit in
around the Diwali in terms of what we
see that around that 4 weeks to 6 weeks,
there is a little bit of a uh different
kind of a mix which gets invoked, but
otherwise, I don't see that there is
going to be a mix which is going to be
very very different in terms of going
forward. Uh the other thing is that uh
currently, as you said rightly, we've
reached about a 40% kind of a gross
margin which is there.
Uh as we see it, a 44-45%
kind of a margin is a little bit
unrealistic in terms of
going forward. I think uh it was also
when possibly the prices
uh were at its lowest in terms of the
inflation was just not there. In fact,
it was more of a deflation at that point
of time to that extent, and therefore,
uh we would kind of really see it that
we keep it in that band of 41 42 42 kind
of a percent in terms of the overall
gross margins going forward. And with
respect to pricing, I think what we are
very clear is that, uh, we would very
clearly look at a certain modeling it
around the price elasticity where we can
see that there is a certain
affordability which we can get to the
customer because we would not like, uh,
that the demand should kind of get
affected and we would be responsive as a
leader in terms of looking at that in
terms of how we would like to kind of
peg the overall pricing. But going
forward in terms of, we would still kind
of see that we would like to maintain
that band of, uh, 18 to 20% from the
point of view of the EBITDA margins
going forward as well. So, I think, uh,
that is the dual role in terms of what
we will keep on playing in terms of
saying that how do we kind of really peg
our pricing, how do we look at our
overall EBITDA margins in terms of this
thing because what we see is that, uh,
this year again the volatility of
inflation will continue to some extent.
We are not getting an indication that,
uh, the second half of the year, uh,
currently is kind of giving us any
comfort that it will be benign in terms
of the inflation from my inflation point
of view. So, I think, uh, we will have
to keep on looking from quarter to
quarter to in terms of how we do. And as
as I said, your price increases will
have to be calibrated to see that, uh,
what gross margins you are maintaining
and, uh, possibly what is the kind of
work which you are doing with respect to
cost saving as we kind of go forward.
So, I think it will be a combination of
all that.
Okay, so that's very very helpful, Amit,
and thank you so much for this.
My second quick question is on decor
business.
And in decor, basically, obviously,
there's a service element, there's a
product element, and then you are
combining various elements together,
including lighting, furniture, design
element,
bathroom fittings to kitchens to it is
the entire repertoire of basically new
home to existing home being renovated.
So, I can clearly see the value
proposition and you also describe this
affordable luxury proposition and so you
are targeting a typical household I can
imagine.
Uh
in that, you know, can I get your
thoughts a little bit more clear as well
here is that
uh you know, whether the real focus is
on selling product and value capture is
largely on the product or traded product
or our own product or services element
uh which are integrated with it. So, my
sense is services should be free and
product is where you're capturing the
value and is a service element is
entirely outsourced and how are you
integrating that because it's a very
complex ecosystem that is interacting.
It's not very simple. It may sound very
simple, but
how are you balancing this so many
elements interacting and have you
executed few projects already and what
was the size of those projects so far in
the month it has been launched and what
is the kind of learning so far? If you
could help us explain the way we can
understand the business and model it
going forward. Theoretically, it can be
a humongous opportunity, but can company
like Asian Paints my worry is that
company like you can capture value in
the product, but not in service.
Services can complicate the hell lot
because it just brings in elements which
you compete with all sorts of random
people. Sorry about long question, but
you get where I'm coming from.
Yeah. No, so just to clarify first of
all, I think we are looking at value in
terms of a combination of offering
inspiration to the customer which is in
terms of visualization. Second in terms
of the qualities or what we bring it in
the product in terms of what we are
offering and the third element which is
very important is the whole area of
execution and bringing delight to the
consumer. So, if you look at today in
the world, there is no player who offers
visualization coupled with execution to
the glory along with basically a product
proposition which is built into that
extent. So, I think what we are trying
is something which is
you know, as you rightly said, it is
complex but it is in-immutable as I
said. It cannot be copied by anyone
because once you build the servicing
edge along with the fact that you have
not only traded product but your own
product which is kind of giving you
margins to that extent and you have a
very strong visualization story which
you are able to give to the customer. I
think it's a lethal combination in terms
of what you can offer to the customer.
Uh we have kind of
gone into all the elements here. If you
look at from the beautiful home service
point of view, we have kind of executed
it across about now I think 900 to about
1,000 customers
across the country and we have done jobs
which vary from as less than as
50,000 to 1 lakh to as high as about 2
crores to 3 crores as well to that
extent for various kinds of customers to
that extent. So, I think we are
getting a very strong hang of it in
terms of what we need to kind of do to
that extent and it is done very strongly
through an angle of supervision which
kind of comes in to that extent because
we feel that if we kind of just leave
the execution to the market, it kind of
really plays havoc in terms of what it
does to the overall product execution
piece and the delight it kind of brings
to the consumer to that extent. So, I
think that is the model in terms of what
we are looking at and especially I think
this model is not applicable for
categories like there could be a
retailer who's just selling bath taps.
Now, if you're selling just bath taps,
it's like basically you he's just
selling taps to a customer to that
extent. But when you come to a beautiful
homes, you are selling the full home to
the customer along with the element of
visualization, product quality and
a certain element of execution which
kind of comes in.
Sure. Thanks so much, Amit. All the best
for this. Thanks a lot.
Thank you, sir. Our next question is
from Percy, who has joined us on Zoom.
Sir, please unmute yourself, state your
name and company name, and ask your
question.
Uh hi, this is Percy Panthaki from IIFL.
Uh sir, this year has been a splendid
year for you with
a very high volume growth of about 30%.
Uh but looking ahead,
I see
sort of two headwinds for you in terms
of
volume growth for FY23. One is the high
base effect that you are sitting on
for FY22
on a comparative YOY basis. Uh that may
dampen your FY23 growth.
Uh and the second is the significant,
almost uh
uh 25% kind of price increases that you
have taken.
Uh which in turn, as you mentioned,
there is some amount of price elasticity
issues there.
So, uh in in light of these two issues,
uh on a YOY basis for FY23 as a whole,
uh do you think it is possible that
volume growth would slip to low
single-digit uh uh or zero kind of
number because we are seeing, of course,
not exactly comparable category, but we
are seeing many FMCG companies
uh now post a 0% kind of volume growth
even with a 8 to 10% kind of price
increase. Uh paints, of course, is less
penetrated, and therefore, you have new
products also, waterproofing, putty,
which are growing much faster, etc. But
just your thoughts on
how
we can look at volume growth for FY23
YOY. Okay. Uh so, first of all, I think
if you look at the CAGRs in terms of
what we have been posting for the 2 and
three years you are seeing that both on
volume and value we have been able to
post very very strong numbers even if
you compare to a relatively normal year
which is 18 19 which is before the two
COVID years to that extent. So I believe
that the company has taken a very very
strong focus in terms of driving that
trajectory
through a range of kind of strategies in
terms of what are involved in terms of
going forward. Second if you look at a
trend of Q4 over volume growth of 48% as
a base you were still able to grow at an
8% and I said that Feb and March were
high
high growth
double digit volume months for us
because this 8% primarily has come
because January was down because of the
COVID to that extent. So despite the
price increases where we realized the
full value in the Q4 month you know we
have seen still a 8% growth with Feb and
March at high digit high double digit
volume growth to that extent. Now which
only gives the indication of the fact
that you are able to kind of still kind
of propel the demand
from the point of view of how customer
is seeing it and we are seeing that
opportunity across the category of
products. So whether it is upgradation
of emulsions whether it is from the
point of view of upgradation of people
to from
economy to premium to premium to luxury
as a pyramid in terms of how you want to
kind of go forward or whether it is in
case of looking at transitioning people
from solvent base to water base or from
the point of view of saying that you put
a regimen of people putting undercoats
to that extent. So I think there is a
range of strategies in terms of what we
are kind of taking and we find that
there are certain categories like
waterproofing and wood finishes which
are also growing quite spectacularly
overall to that extent in addition to
the fact that you are getting a lot of
innovations in the market. So I think we
are pretty confident that going forward
despite the
base as you rightly mentioned of 31%
volume growth that we should be
definitely kind of look at if nothing
less that you know something like
definitely a double digit volume growth
going forward is what we are definitely
endeavoring in terms of going forward.
And we think that it is possible given
the range of strategies in terms of what
we are taking and the fact that this
year we are saying that if it is a COVID
free year, we definitely see that there
is a lot of pent-up demand of the last 2
years which will aid this kind of a
strategy of growth.
Thank you, sir. We'll be taking our last
question now from Mr. Sujay Kamat
who will join us on Zoom. Sir, please
unmute yourself, state your name and
company name and ask your question.
Yeah, hi.
Thanks a lot for taking my question.
My question is a little more longer
term, you know,
I understand you understand the
long-term growth of the industries. So,
on one side, if I look at you know
organized players such as you,
over the last in fact if I go back to
some of the previous presentations that
you gave, it appears that over the last
3-4 years you have actually doubled your
volume growth your volumes which is
amazing on the decorative side.
But when I look at you know data like
TiO2 consumption in the country which is
basically a mix of imports as well as
domestic production,
you know, TiO2 demand in in India has
only grown at 7% over the last 10 years.
In fact, it's even slower over the last
3-4 years. So, I'm just trying to you
know connect
the demand for TiO2 versus the kind of
growth that the organized sector is
witnessing. I mean, something like 100%
growth over the last 4 years.
And you know, in that context, how does
one look at uh you know, the size you
know, the proportion that organized
sector capture and organized and how
does one look at long-term growth?
Okay, my first question.
Okay, so let me just answer that
straight away. So if you look at various
profile of products,
you know, they have a very different
level of TiO2 consumption depending on
what the product is. So right from an
undercoat to
a top coat which is economy to mid-end
to high-end, every product will have a
very very different level of TiO2
consumption. So you can't correlate
paint growth to the TiO2 consumption
straight away to that extent because it
might not be a straight correlation but
would be a complex correlation in terms
of how it kind of comes by. Point one.
Second is that today TiO2 being the most
costly element in paints,
all companies are looking at seeing lots
of measures in terms of how they can
bring down the TiO2 consumption both
from the point of view of innovation in
manufacturing, better dispersion
technologies and also looking at
a lot of alternate raw materials which
have come in the last about 3 to 4 years
which basically kind of decrease the
TiO2 consumption in the paint. So this
category is what we call as the
opacifiers which basically gives the
hiding to the paint and basically
removes the need in terms of putting
that quantum of TiO2 into the paint to
that extent. So I think given these kind
of overall measures which are happening
and then there are various grades of
TiO2 which is the chloride and the
sulfates and so on so forth to that
extent which kind of gets used in
different percentages again depending on
the product which is there to that
extent. So I think given this whole area
in terms of what you kind of look at, it
would not be clearly correlatable with
basically the TiO2 consumption and as I
said that the larger imperative of the
entire industry is that
uh they are looking at more and more
places they can replace TiO2 with better
technologies both on manufacturing as
well as alternate items.
That was our last question. May I now
request Mr. Amit Singal to deliver his
closing remarks, please.
Okay, I think good. I think we tried to
see that we could kind of give you some
larger kind of
clarification and that is why we had a
slightly longer presentation today in
terms of the various aspects.
I think thank you all for coming today
and really asking some incisive
questions which are there. I think it's
always good to kind of see that we are
able to answer those questions and give
you some clarity in terms of how we are
proceeding and what is really happening
with the organization. So, thank you
once again for coming for this investor
conference and have have a have a great
season ahead. Thank you.